<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-24T18:40:35+02:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html"></title><subtitle>My personal website.</subtitle><author><name>Wai kon Tse</name><email>waikon at waikontse dot info</email></author><entry><title type="html">Flow - Worst methodology ever</title><link href="/blog/software%20development/flow-methodology/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Flow - Worst methodology ever" /><published>2019-10-16T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-10-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/software%20development/flow-methodology</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/software%20development/flow-methodology/">&lt;p&gt;A satirical talk about current agile practices in the real world.
Both funny and satisfying as the same moment.
Throwing jabs at tools and methodologies that managers accepts as holy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Satire aside, the talks highlights anti-patterns in the current agile practices.
Things that we as developers perceive as non-productive, but only as a gut feeling, the authors provides evidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To conclude the talk, the authors provided tips and guides as how to approach software development as originally intended by the agile manifesto.
Personally, the best advice given was to just pick the things that work for your team and situation.
There is no one-size fits all. Empower the team, give them more autonomy.
No blame culture, empower them to learn and try new stuff.
Don’t introduce fear, fear is a powerful emotion and makes people go on the defensive and diminishes productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bring in change in baby steps, change makes people defensive.
Change means moving out of your comfort zone and brings emotional stress with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resources: &lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/aahoogendoorn/flow-the-official-worst-software-development-approach-in-history&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://kimvanwilgen.com/&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://agilemanifesto.org/&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Wai kon Tse</name><email>waikon at waikontse dot info</email></author><category term="flow" /><category term="Kim van Wilgen" /><category term="Sander Hoogendoorn" /><summary type="html">A satirical talk about current agile practices in the real world. Both funny and satisfying as the same moment. Throwing jabs at tools and methodologies that managers accepts as holy.</summary></entry></feed>